it's the real news
I'm Marinette a the convictions Tuesday
of Palme an important and Michael Cohen
have fueled speculation that these two
men may have something to offer Robert
Muller in his investigation of President
Trump and his alleged ties to alleged
Russian meddling well if so and that's a
very big if Cohen and metaphor would add
to the list of people who Donald Trump
has to worry about another is possibly
former CIA director John Brennan Brennan
is called Trump treasonous and guilty of
high crimes and misdemeanors because
Trump resisted endorsing US intelligence
claims about Russian meddling Trump
responded last week by revoking Brennan
security clearance Brennan then
responded by calling Trump drunk on
power the fact that he's using a
security clearance of a former CIA
director as a pawn in his public
relations strategy I think is just so
reflective of somebody who quite frankly
don't want to use this term maybe but
he's drunk on power he really is and I
think he's abusing the powers of that
office I think right now this country is
in a crisis in terms of what mr. Trump
has done and is liable to do join me is
John Kiriakou he is a former CIA analyst
who went to prison for exposing the
CIA's torture program he is also a
best-selling author and co-host of the
podcast and radio show loud and clear
welcome John Kerry aku where do you
stand on this Trump Brennan feud Trump
criticized for politicizing the issue of
security clearances but I also know that
you are not personally a big fan of
Brennan or a big believer in his
personal integrity no I have never been
John and I go back almost 30 years I
worked for him several different times
while I was at the CIA and I can tell
you that John really is the consummate
overachiever he made a couple of really
smart
perhaps lucky political moves and so he
has succeeded beyond even his own
wildest dreams
um you know John throws around the word
treason or treatments quite often
treason is actually defined in the
Constitution it's providing aid and
comfort to the enemy at a time of war
treason is a death penalty charge
everyone in American history who has
been charged with treason has been
sentenced to death about half of those
executions have been carried out so what
John is saying is that the President of
the United States ought to be executed
now we've seen no evidence yet of
Russian collusion or the Trump campaigns
collusion with the Russian government
all we have is John Brennan and the
likes of John Brennan telling us to take
his word for it because if we had seen
when he's seen we would know well you
know what John Brennan also told us that
there was no torture program he lied
about that John Brennan told us that
there was no extraordinary rendition
program he lied about that he told us
there was no system of secret prisons
that was a lie
he told us that he hadn't ordered CIA
officers to hack into the Senate
intelligence committees computers that
was a lot but on this he's telling us to
take his word for it but why in the
world would we take his word for it if
everything else that the man has said
has been alive let me say one other
thing about John Brennan John makes it
crystal clear to anyone who will listen
in Washington that the reason he is so
out there against Donald Trump is that
he desperately wants to be secretary of
defense in the next democratic
administration John's not a lawyer he's
not a lobbyist and so he has to remain
relevant and the way that he has seen to
keep himself relevant is to go on CNN
and to go on MSNBC and to me he's
outrageous accusations just so that he
continually gets press coverage that's
what he's done and it's going to
backfire yeah and this is the problem
where you know in a bid to take down
Trump for you know reasons that I think
you and I can sympathize sympathize with
because we don't share John Trump's
politics obviously but in a bid to do
that it means that many liberals will
endorse anybody who is challenging him
including someone like John Brennan who
might not necessary
we be going after shop for the same
reasons that the rest of us have because
we actually opposed his policies is used
indicated I mean Brennan to attack Trump
for abuse of power is ironic given the
the short list you gave there a
Brennan's record including spying on the
Senate when they were trying to expose
his torture program is ABC's torture
program and then lying about it and also
I want to play a few more clips of John
Brennan because it's also interesting
he's since after saying this thing about
trees and he's walk that back and he's
also indicated that he doesn't even have
any evidence of this conspiracy that he
seems so confident notes so first let's
go to John Brennan again I'm speaking to
Rachel Maddow where he actually told her
that he doesn't actually mean what he
said about Trump committing treason for
the president United States to continue
to prevaricate on this issue I think
does a great injustice and a disservice
to the men and women of the intelligence
law enforcement community and does a
great disservice to the Citizens United
States and that's why I said it was
nothing short of treasonous I didn't
mean that he committed treason but it
was a term that I used nothing short of
treasonous well you didn't mean that he
committed treason now I said it's
nothing short of treasonous that was the
term that I use yeah that's that if we
if we diagram the sentence nothing short
of treasonous means it's treason so
that's John Brennan saying he did not
mean to say that Trump committed treason
essentially walking back the comments
that got retweeted a million times and
gotten a lot of attention we began the
former CI director called the sitting
president treasonous and then in the
same interview Brennan also spoke about
what he knows about alleged Trump Russia
collusion which he admitted is basically
nothing more than what has been reported
in the media there is collusion I think
in open sight now because so many things
I've learned since I left office because
of what has appeared in the press you
know the Trump Tower meeting with Don
jr. and others and I also when I was CI
director I didn't know that it was the
day that mr. Trump basically gave a
public call to the Russians to find
Hillary Clinton's emails
that it would fact was that same day
that the GRU was actively looking for it
so there is collusion in plain sight so
that is John Brennan speaking to Rachel
Maddow so so John there you go we have
Brennan walking back what he said about
treason and then getting a little bit
testy when he's called on it by Maddow
and then saying that he actually doesn't
even really know anything beyond what
the rest of us have heard in the media
and is talking about Trump Tower which
has been you know analyzed elsewhere we
don't have to go into but the point is
he seems to be making these really
explosive pronouncements based on
essentially nothing yeah
and that's very much John John's an
alpha dog he's always been like that
he's always been the first one to pick a
fight or the first one and to raise his
voice he even told Rachel Maddow in that
interview that his Irish was up and and
so he may have said things that he
didn't actually mean what he was
referring to of course was what you just
said that the president committed
treason well he didn't really commit in
treaties and he kind of maybe committed
treason that's just John that's that's
how he is and there are others like John
Hill mud does the same thing Phil mud
has has called Donald Trump a petulant
child
he said that Trump need pacifier and a
new rattle but it's the same thing with
John in that films trying to get his own
show on CNN and Phil wants to be the
deputy director of the FBI or the deputy
director of the CIA I mean that's
Washington that's just the way it is and
let me see something big - I've written
extensively about this you don't have to
pick a side you have a scenario where
there's no good guy we don't have to
love Donald Trump and hate the CIA or
vice versa you can you can not like
Donald Trump and not agree with Donald
Trump's policies but then not throw your
body in with the beep state and the CIA
and the FBI and the likes of John
Brennan our democracy is broken right
now we need to take it back at the brass
roots we need to throw the bums out of
Congress and we need to elect people who
are going to exercise real oversight but
we don't have to throw our lot in with
either
from or job well john korea who will
leave it there John Kiriakou is a
best-selling author coast of the radio
show and podcast loud and clear and a
former CIA whistleblower John Kerry
Yahoo thanks very much my pleasure
thanks take care and thank you for
joining us on the real news